Guide to the Social Science Data Archive, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Social Science Data Archive, Yale University, records
1968-2003
RU 1008
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
The records consist of annual reports and general administrative records of the Social Science Data Archive (administered by the Yale Social Science Library) and acquisition records of the Roper Center for Public Opinion Research.
Yale University. Social Science Data Archive
Yale University. Library
Yale University. Social Science Libraries and Information Services
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Social Science Library, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of annual reports and general administrative records of the Social Science Data Archive (administered by the Yale Social Science Library) and acquisition records of the Roper Center for Public Opinion Research.
Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; Data libraries; Roper Center for Public Opinion Research; Yale University. Library; Yale University. Social Science Data Archive
- Administrative records of the Social Science Data Archive (SSDA)and acquisition records of the Roper Center for Public Opinion Collection, 1968-2003; Accession 2007-A-011
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
  - Annual Reports, 1973-1983 (Box 1)
  - Data Processing
    - SSDA Statlab tape procedures, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Roper Guide Revisions, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Data Orders
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1990-91 (Box 1)
    - 1992-93 (Box 1)
    - 1993-94 (Box 1)
    - 1994-95 (Box 1)
    - 1995-96 (Box 1)
    - 1996-97 (Box 1)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Roper Data Orders, 1991-2000 (Box 1)
  - Roper Prices and Costs, circa 1988-1995 (Box 1)
  - Restricted data
    - ICPSR Restricted use data, 1998-2003 (Box 1)
    - SSDA Releases for NCHS tapes, circa 1980s-90s (Box 1)
    - SSDA restricted data files specs, 1979-1984 (Box 1)
    - NCHS Report, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
    - CT Blood Pressure Releases, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - NLS - Youth Cohort Geocode, 1981 (Box 1)
    - SSDA National Center for Health Statistics Tapes, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Roper Collection Administrative Records
    - Yale Roper relations, 1970-1980 (Box 1)
    - Inventory of paper Roper questionnaires at SSL, circa 1980-1990's (Box 1)
  - Inventories of SSDA Data Holdings
    - Tape reels, circa 1990s (Box 2)
    - Political Science Research Library, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Spires Mainframe Database ID 3-742, 2 volumes, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Roper Center for Public Opinion, circa 1980's - 1990's (Box 3)
    - Roper Tapes at Yale - with archive numbers, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Roper listing of Yale data by DSN, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Binder - Codebook, circa 1980s (Box 3)
    - Roper Center Foreign Collection, -1978 (Box 3)
    - Migration records, circa 1990s (Box 3)
    - Deleted Records (Box 3)
    - Cartridges to replace (Box 3)
    - Correspondence related to migration of SSDA from Yale VM to statlab server, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Roper tape reel inventory, circa 1990's (Box 3)
  - Roper Data Holdings
    - Roper Center for Public Opinion, circa 1980-1990s (Box 4)
    - Great Britain - Uganda - narrative descriptions (Box 4)
    - Africa - Ghana - narrative descriptions (Box 4)
    - United States - Yugoslavia (Box 4)
  - Roper Center for Public Opinion Research
    - Data Acquisitions
      - 1989 Jan (Box 4)
      - 1989 Jul - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1989 Jul (Box 4)
      - 1990 Jan - Jun (Box 4)
      - 1990 Jul - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1991 Jan - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1992 Jan - Jun (Box 4)
      - 1992 Jul - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1993 Jul - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1993 Jan - Jun (Box 4)
      - 1994 Jan -Jun (Box 4)
      - 1994 Jul - Dec (Box 4)
      - 1995 Jan - Jun (Box 4)
      - 1995 Dec (Box 4)
    - Data Holdings
      - Roper Center Question Index, circa 1980's (Box 5)
      - American Surveys Study Inventory, circa 1968-70's (Box 5)
      - United States Information Agency Data Set Listing, 1975 (Box 5)
      - United States Information Agency Report and Data Listing, 2 Volumes, 1968 (Box 5)
      - The Roper Center American Collection Volume 5, 1987 January (Box 5)
      - The Roper Center American Collections Volume IV, 1986 June (Box 5)
      - Profiles of the Major American Collections Volume VI, 1987 July (Box 5)
    - Data Acquisitions
      - 1984 Dec (Box 5)
      - 1984 Jan (Box 5)
      - 1984 Jul (Box 5)
      - 1985 Jun (Box 5)
      - 1986 Jan (Box 5)
      - 1986 Jun (Box 5)
      - 1987 Jan (Box 5)
      - 1987 Jul (Box 5)
      - 1988 Jan (Box 5)
      - 1988 Jul (Box 5)